Carl Neuberg Papers ca.1880-1956 1940-1956 Mss.Ms.Coll.4
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1970-1975; 3 lin. feet
  - Schoenebeck, Otto von, 1947-56 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Schoenlicht, A, 1944 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Schreiber, n.d. (Box Series I: 14)
  - Schuchardt, Werner & Edith, 1951-56 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Schulsinger Brothers, 1943 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Schulz, Gertrude D, 1946 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Schwabe, Moshe, 1952 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Schwarz Laboratories, 1942-55 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Schwarzkopf Laboratories, 1954 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Schweitzer, Albert, 1947 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Schweizerische Ferment A.G., 1947-48 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Schwenk, Ervin, 1942-55 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Scott, W. D., 1949 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Scriban, Rene, 1953 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Seeliger, 1953-54 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Seidel, Ina, 1953 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Seligman, Arnold M., 1952 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Seligmann, E., 1947 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Semmens, Elizabeth S., 1948 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Senior, Edwin, 1946 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Senn, Vincent J., 1946 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Sevag, M. G., 1943-54 (Box Series I: 14)
  - Shapiro, S., 1947 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Sharples Chemicals Inc., 1942-56 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Shemin, David, 1954 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Shindler, Gerd H., 1948 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Shiono, G., 1953 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Shirk, Harold G., 1954 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Sigma Xi, 1943-44 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Simon, Ernst, 1941-56 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Simpson Coal & Chemical Corp., 1956 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Singer, Th. P., 1952-53 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Singher, Heron O., 1949 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Sioux Honey Association, 1949 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Sizer, Irwin W., 1947 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Sky and Telescope, 1942 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Wm. Sloan Associates, 1954-55 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Smith, G. Frederick, 1952-54 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Smith, Paul F., 1955 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Snapper, I., 1956 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Snyder, H. R., 1948 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Sobel, Albert Edward, 1951-55 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Sobotka, Harry H., 1943-56 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Society for the Protection of Science and Learning, 1942-47 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Soskin, Samuel, 1943 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Soubotian, Boris, 1953-55 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Southland Chemical Company, 1946 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Spencer, Brian, 1955 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Spiegelman, S., 1948 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Spoehr, A. H., 1947 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Springer, 1945 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Springer, Julius, 1917 (Box Series I: 15)
  - E.R. Squibb & Sons, 1948-53 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Squibb Institute for Medical Research, 1949 (Box Series I: 15)
  - A.E. Staley Manufacturing Co., 1941-52 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Standard Brands, Inc., 1942-56 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Standard Oil Co., 1946-48 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Standard Scientific Supply Corp., 1942 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Staudinger, Herman, 1952-53 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Stauffer Chemical Co., 1948 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Frederick Stearns & Co., 1944 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Steenbock, Harry, 1942-56 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Stein, William H, 1948 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Steinherz, Dezsoe, 1946 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Sterling Winthrop Research Inst., 1946 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Stern, Ch., 1946 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Stern, Kurt G., 1943-56 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Stern, Rudolf A., 1947 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Stelten, M. R., 1946 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Stodola, Frank H., 1956 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Stöhr, R, 1949-51 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Stoll, Arthur, 1947-48 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Strauss, Eduard, 1943-48 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Strauss, Mrs. Eduard, 1952 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Stricks, Walter, 1951 (Box Series I: 15)
  - John & E. Sturge, Ltd., 1949-53 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Sturman, Robert M, 1954 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Stynier, Frederic E, 1955-56 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Sugar Research Foundation, 1944 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Sumner, James Batcheller, 1955 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Sunkist Growers (Box Series I: 15)
  - Suomalainen, Heikki, 1946-47 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Swain, William M, 1951 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Swift & Company, 1944-45 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Symposium on the Respiratory Enzymes... (Program), September 1941 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Syracuse University. School of Medicine, 1942 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Syrup Service Corporation, 1942 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Szemsoe, Bela, 1952-55 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Tabakforschung, Bundesanstalt fòr, 1955 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Takamine Laboratories, 1946-53 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Taub, 1942 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Tauber, Harry, 1943-55 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Taylor, Hugh S., 1948-49 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Telschow, Ernst, 1951-56 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Tennessee Eastman Corp., 1946 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Teshigahara, T, 1953 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Thannhauser, Sigfried Joseph, 1947-48 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Thilo, Erich, 1951-56 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Thomas, Karl, 1949-54 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Thomas, P., 1947-48 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Timpe, Winfried, 1953 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Tipson, R. Stuart, 1948 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Tishler, Max, 1953 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Tobacco- Misc., 1940s (Box Series I: 15)
  - Tomita, Masaji, 1953-56 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Traverso, G. B., 1949 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Treibs, W, 1952 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Tscherniak, A, 1941-42 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Tuchman, Lester, 1953 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Turkeye Seker Fabrikalari, 1952 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Turner, William J, 1948 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Ulrich, Karl, 1953-55 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Umbreit, W w, 1943-44 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Underkofler, Leland A, 1954 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Unger, Marianne, 1942-43 (Box Series I: 15)
  - Unidentified correspondents, 1952 (Box Series I: 15)
  - U.S Atomic Energy Commission, 1949-53; 4 folders (Box Series I: 16)
  - U.S Atomic Energy Commission - Security Clearance, 1950-51 (Box Series I: 16)
  - U.S. Bureau of Mines, 1956 (Box Series I: 16)
  - U.S. Civil Service Commission, 1942 (Box Series I: 16)
  - U.S. Coordinator of Information, 1942 (Box Series I: 16)
  - U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1944-50; 2 folders (Box Series I: 16)
  - U.S. Department of Defense. Armed Services Technical Information Agency., 1953-55 (Box Series I: 16)
  - U.S. Department of Justice., 1943 (Box Series I: 16)
  - U.S. Department of the Interior. Geological Survey., 1956 (Box Series I: 16)
  - U.S Department of the Navy. Office of Naval Research., 1950-55; 4 folders (Box Series I: 16)
  - U.S. Public Health Service (folders 1-4), 1943-55; 4 folders (Box Series I: 16)
  - U.S. Public Health Service (folders 5-8), 1943-55; 4 folders (Box Series I: 17)
  - U.S. War Department., 1948 (Box Series I: 17)
  - U.S. War Manpower Commission. Office for Emergency Management, n.d. (Box Series I: 17)
  - Universal Jewish Encyclopedia, 1942 (Box Series I: 17)
  - University of California Los Angeles, 1943 (Box Series I: 17)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1947 (Box Series I: 17)
  - University of Washington. Dept. of Oceanography., 1954 (Box Series I: 17)
  - University of Wisconsin Press, 1942 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Urban & Schwarzenberg, 1949 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Ursprung, Felix, 1946 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Valco, Emery I., 1954 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Van Camp Laboratories, 1943 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Van Loon, J., 1940 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Van Slyke, Donald D., 1951 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Vanadium Corp. of America, 1942 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Vance, John E., 1948-49 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Veibel, Stig, 1947-54 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Venkataraman, K., 1947 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Vercellone, Alberto, 1954 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Verona Chemical Co., 1942 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Vickery, H. B, 1943 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Victor Chemical Works, 1941-53 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Du Vigneaud, Vincent, 1947-55 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Virginia-Carolina Chemical Corp., 1954-55 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Virtanen, Arturri, 1946-55 (Box Series I: 17)
  - von Vitzthum, Marie Helene, 1955-56 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Vogt, Marthe, 1947 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Voorhis, 1940 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Wachtel, Henry K, 1947 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Waelseh, Heinrich, 1943-56 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Wagner, Robert F, 1942 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Wagner-Jauregg, Th., 1952-56 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Wagreich, Harry, 1947-48 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Wainio, Walter-W, 1953 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Waksman, Selman A., n.d. (Box Series I: 17)
  - Walbaum, Karl E., 1942 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Wald, George, 1952-55 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Waldschmidt-Leitz, E, 1951 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Walker, T. K., 1947-53 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Wallerstein, James S, 1943 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Wallerstein Laboratories, 1942-53 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Walti, A., 1942-46 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Walton, Eda Lou, 1942 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Warburg, Otto, 1948-56 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Warner, Robert C., 1955 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Warwick Chemical Company, 1943 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Wastel, H, 1946 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Webley, D., 1948 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Weidlein, E. R., 1952 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Weil, E. J. Bruno, 1947-53 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Weil, Richard, 1948 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Weinberger, Ruth, 1947 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Weiner, A., 1943 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Weiss, Theodore J., 1952 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Weiss, Ulrich, 1953 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Weitzel, G, 1953-54 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Weizmann, Chaim, 1945 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Weizmann Institute of Science, 1952 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Wenger, P. E., 1952-53 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Wenger, T, 1949 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Werk, Otto, 1955 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Werkman, C. H., 1942-47 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Wertheim, Hughes, 1942 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Wertheimer, E., 1943-45 (Box Series I: 17)
  - West, Philip W., 1948 (Box Series I: 17)
  - Westvaco, 1951-53 (Box Series I: 17)
  - White, E. V., 1948 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Who's Who in World Jewry, 1953 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Wibaut, J. P., 1946-48 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Wieland, Heinrich, 1946-55 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Wiener, Arthur S., 1947 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Wieringa, K. T., 1946-47 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Wilheim, Robert, 1954 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Willstaedt, Harry, 1947 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Willstätter, Richard, n.d. (Box Series I: 18)
  - Wilson Laboratories, 1944 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Windaus, Adolf, 1947-52 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Windisch, Fritz, 1948-56 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Winternitz, Paul F, 1944 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Winters, Joseph, 1943 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Winterstein, Alexander, 1948 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Winthrop Chemical Co., 1942-46 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Wohlgemuth, Julius, 1942-46 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Wolfrom, Melville L., 1943-56 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Wood, Harland G., 1952-53 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Woodard, Helen Quincy, 1942 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Woodman, H, 1947 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Woodruff, J, 1943 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Woods Hole Marine Biological Laboratories, 1952-55 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Woolley, D, 1942 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Womall, A, 1951 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Wuest, H, 1943-44 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Wyandotte Chemicals Corp., 1944-51 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Wynder, Ernest L (Box Series I: 18)
  - Yamada, Masakazu, 1953-54 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Yamafuji, Kazuo, 1951-52 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Yasuda, STanley K, 1954 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Young, F. G., 1949 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Zamorano, Jaime Iragorri, 1952 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Zechmeister, L., 1944-47 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Zeitschrift für die Zuckerindustrie, 1954 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Zeitschrift für Physiologische Chemie, 1952 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Zeitschrift für Spiritusindustrie, 1940 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Zerban, F, 1946-47 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Zerner, Ernst, 1943 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Ziffer, R, 1947-49 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Zondek, Bernhard, 1942 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Zondek, Hermann, 1947 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Zondek, Marie, 1942-43 (Box Series I: 18)
  - Zuelzer, Georg, 1943 (Box Series I: 18)
- Series II. Notebooks, 1933-1955
  Notebooks relating to Neuberg's research and reading in biochemistry, dating almost exclusively from after his move to New York University in 1946.
  - "Amine", 1949; Red spiral binding (Box Series II-1)
  - I., ca.1950; Hard bound (Box Series II-1)
  - II., n.d.; Hardbound (Box Series II-1)
  - III., n.d.; Hardbound (Box Series II-1)
  - Lab notes, 1948; "The Spiral" (Box Series II-1)
  - Lab notes, 1948; Red spiral binding (Box Series II-1)
  - "Mentholgl...", n.d.; "The Gyral" (Box Series II-1)
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1948; 126p. 3-ring binder (Box Series II-1)
  - Miscellaneous notes, n.d.; Grey paper binding, "New York University" (Box Series II-1)
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1933; Purple paper binding (Box Series II-1)
  - "Nieder zucker", n.d.; 2p. Red paper binding (Box Series II-1)
  - Notebook (1), n.d.; Black paper binding (Box Series II-1)
  - Notebook (2), n.d.; Black paper binding (Box Series II-1)
  - "Protokollbuch", n.d.; Red paper binding (Box Series II-1)
  - Research notebook", ca.1945; 144p. Red paper binding (Box Series II-1)
  - "Themata I", 1945; 144p. Red paper binding (Box Series II-1)
  - "Themata II", 1945; 144p. Red paper binding (Box Series II-1)
  - I., 1950; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - II., 1950; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - III., 1950; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - IV., 1950; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - V., 1950; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - VI., 1950; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - VII., 1950; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - VIII., 1950; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - IX., 1950; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - I., 1953; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - MK I., 1954; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - MK II., 1954; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - MK III., 1954; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - MK IV., 1954; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - No. III, 1955; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - Analysen, n.d.; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - Dinitro..., ca.1950; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - Inventar I, n.d.; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - Inventar II, n.d.; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - Naphtaresorcinol, 1952; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - Solutions zähne, n.d.; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - Themata III, n.d.; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - Thiophosphate, n.d.; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - Thio..., n.d.; Spiral binding (Box Series II-2)
  - Unidentified, n.d.; 2 vols. (Box Series II-2)
  - Carbaminate MK II, 1950 (Box Series II-3)
  - Carbaminate MK I, 1955 (Box Series II-3)
  - Carbaminate MK II, 1955 (Box Series II-3)
  - Carbaminate MK III, 1955 (Box Series II-3)
  - Carbaminate I, n.d. (Box Series II-3)
  - Carbaminate II, n.d. (Box Series II-3)
  - Carbaminate III, 1955 (Box Series II-3)
  - Carbaminate IV (Fisch), n.d. (Box Series II-3)
  - Frem. Prob., n.d. (Box Series II-3)
  - H.L., 1955 (Box Series II-3)
  - H.L., n.d. (Box Series II-3)
  - Leber Notizen, n.d.; Bound in black (Box Series II-3)
  - Miscellaneous notes, ca.1945; "Blue bell" (Box Series II-3)
  - Miscellaneous notes, n.d.; 2 vols., Spiral bound (Box Series II-3)
  - Miscellaneous notes, n.d.; No cover (Box Series II-3)
  - Miscellaneous notes, n.d.; Looseleaf (Box Series II-3)
  - Phosphate, n.d., ca.1950-1955 (Box Series II-3)
  - Phosphorylation etc., 1950-1955 (Box Series II-3)
  - Solutions, n.d. (Box Series II-3)
  - Versamstlist(?), n.d. (Box Series II-3)
  - Woods Hole, 1955 (Box Series II-3)
- Series III. Miscellaneous material, 1933-1949
  Miscellaneous letters and copies of printed and typescript materials. The bulk of the series is comprised of letters written to Neuberg in celebration of his 70th birthday, 1947.
  - 70th Birthday Greetings, 1947 (Box Series III - 1, Folder 1)
  - 70th Birthday Greetings, 1947 (Box Series III-1, Folder 2)
  - 70th Birthday Greetings, 1947 (Box Series III-1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous items, 1947-ca.1950 (Box Series III-1)